[{"question":"<p><strong>Blackboard chalk is a mixture of limestone and gypsum. A piece of blackboard chalk weighing 5.42 was immersed in HCl. The CO<sub>2<\/sub> produced weighed 1.11g. What is the percentage of limestone in the chalk?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["67.0%","53.3%","50.8%","46.5%"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>In the Lassaine's test for the halogens, the sodium fusion extract is acidified and then treated with silver nitrate. A pale yellow precipitate soluble in ammonium hydroxide shows the presence of<\/strong><\/p>","options":["fluorine","chlorine","bromine","iodine"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Given the half-cell reaction, 2Br&nbsp;\u2192 Br<sub>2<\/sub>, how many moles of electron will be required to produce 0.56 dm<sup>3<\/sup> of bromine at s.t.p? [molar volume of gas at s.t.p = 22.4dm<sup>3<\/sup> ]<\/strong><\/p>","options":["0.05","0.10","0.20","1.00"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The basic tenet of valence bond electron pair repulsiontheory is that the pairs of electrons making the sigma bonds dictate the shape of molecules. The pi-bonds often encountrer in some molecules serve to<\/strong><\/p>","options":["distort the shape of molecules","after the angle between the atoms in the molecules","shorten the sigma bonds in molecules","explain the shape of the molecules"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The equilibrium constant at constant pressure , Kp for the reaction,<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>2NO<sub>(g)<\/sub>&nbsp;+ Cl<sub>2(g)<\/sub>&nbsp;\u21942NOCl<sub>(g)<\/sub> is 800. The partial pressure of the gas mixture at equilibrium are 0.02 atm each for NOCl in the mixture?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["0.02 atm.","6.4 x 10<sup><\/sup> atm.","0.04 atm.","0.08 atm."],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The enthalpy changes for the atomization of methane and ethane are 1648 and 2820 kJ mol<sup>-1<\/sup> respectively. The C-C mean bond dissociation energy in kJ&nbsp;mol<sup>-1<\/sup> is therefore<\/strong><\/p>","options":["348","-348","1176","-1176"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>What volume of 0.750 mol dm<sup>-<\/sup><sup>3<\/sup> Na <sub>2<\/sub> CO<sub>3<\/sub> solution could be diluted to 250 cm<sup>3<\/sup> to reduce the concentration to 0.025 mol&nbsp;dm<sup>-<\/sup><sup>3<\/sup> ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["16.0cm<sup>3<\/sup>","14.2cm<sup>3<\/sup>","10.4cm<sup>2<\/sup>","8.3cm<sup>3<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>An organic compound with the molecular of&nbsp; C<sub>4<\/sub>H<sub>8<\/sub>O has the Isomers (i) butanal (ii) cyclobutanol (iii)cyclobutanone (iv)2 -methylpropanal<\/strong><\/p>","options":["(i) and (ii)","(i), (ii) and (iv)","(i), (ii) and (iii)","(ii) and (iv)"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>0.125 mol of magnesium is dropped into 25cm<sup>3<\/sup> of 4.0 mol dm<sup>-3<\/sup> HCl. How many moles of hydrogen gas are evolved?[Mg 24]<\/strong><\/p>","options":["0.050","0250","0.125","0.063"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is thermally stable?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["CuCO<sub>3<\/sub>","Pb(NO<sub>3<\/sub>)<sub>2<\/sub>","Na<sub>2<\/sub>NO<sub>3<\/sub>","Na<sub>2<\/sub>CO<sub>3<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>An atom has a core and outside the core an electron occupies an orbital for which the principal quantum number, n=4, I=0, m0 and s+1\/2% or -1\/2%. The atom is likely to be&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["boron","sodium","potassium","fluorine"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>A chloroform solution of pure organic compound was spotted to a distance 0.80 cm from the base of a 20cm long chromatoplate. If the compound has the Rt value of 0.50 and moves half way up the 20cm long plate, what is the distance of the solvent front from the top of the plate upon elution?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["0.80cm","1.0cm``","1.2cm","1.4cm"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Platinum electrodes are dipped into copper sulphate solution in a voltmeter. The solution left after electrolysis is&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["clear","blue","purple","pale green"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The equilibrium constant, Kc for the reaction, NO<sub>(g)<\/sub> + 1\/2 O2<sub>(g)<\/sub>&nbsp;&rarr; NO<sub>(g)<\/sub>, is 35.2. What is the value of Kc for the reaction, NO<sub>2(g)<\/sub> NO<sub>(g)<\/sub> +1\/2 O2 <sub>(g)<\/sub>?&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["35.2","17.6","2.84x10<sup>-2<\/sup>","1.24x10<sup>3<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>CH<sub>3<\/sub>CH<sub>2<\/sub>Cl + NaOH&nbsp;&rarr; CH<sub>3<\/sub>CH<sub>2<\/sub>OH + NaCl<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The above reaction is best described will proceed to form the products by a process known as<\/strong><\/p>","options":["nucleophilic addition","nucleophilic substitition","electrophilic addition","electrophilic substitution"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>What quantity of current is required to deposit 2.4g of copper in a period of 750 seconds during an electrolytic deposition process? [Cu=64, 1F = 96500 coul mol<sup>-1<\/sup>]<\/strong><\/p>","options":["9.65A","10.81A","12.33A","15.54A"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The standard reduction potentials for the following half-cell reactions are, 2H<sub>2<\/sub>O<sub>(l)<\/sub> =O2<sub>(g)<\/sub> + 4H<sup>+<\/sup><sub>(aq)<\/sub> + 4e E<sup>0<\/sup> = -1.23V 2H<sub>2<\/sub>O<sub>2<\/sub>(i) = 2O<sub>2(g)<\/sub> +4H<sup>+<\/sup><sub>(ag)<\/sub> + 4eE<sup>o<\/sup> __0.68V<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>What is the E<sup>o<\/sup> for the reaction, 2H<sub>2<\/sub>O<sub>2(i)<\/sub>=2H<sub>2<\/sub>O<sub>2(g)<\/sub> + O<sub>2(g)<\/sub> at 298K?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["-0.68V","-1.23V","+0.55V","+1.91V"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Bonding in ammonium chloride is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["ionic, covalent and dative","ionic and covalent","covalent and dative","ionic"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>when CuSO<sub>4&nbsp;<\/sub>soultuion is treated with ammonia solution drop by drop till it is added in excess, a precipitate is the first formed which then dissolves in excess to give a deep blue solution. The deep blue solution is Cu(OH)<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Cu(OH)<sub>4<\/sub>","[Cu(NH<sub>3<\/sub>)<sub>4<\/sub>](OH)<sub>2<\/sub>","CuSO<sub>4<\/sub>","[Cu(NH<sub>3<\/sub>)<sub>2<\/sub>]SO<sub>4<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>if 7.0g of ethane at s.t.p occupy 5.6dm<sup>3<\/sup>, What volume will 7.5g of ethane t the same condition occupy? [C=12; H=1; GMV at s.t.p= 22.4dm<sup>3<\/sup>]<\/strong><\/p>","options":["6.0dm<sup>3<\/sup>","5.6dm<sup>3<\/sup>","5.2dm<sup>3<\/sup>","9.4dm<sup>3<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>The name of the CH<sub>3<\/sub>&nbsp;\u2015 OCOC<sub>2<\/sub>H<sub>5<\/sub> is&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["methoxyethane","methylpropanoate","ethylethanoate","propylmethanoate"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of these elements has the highest first ionization energy?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Rb","Li","Na","K"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the followings is responsible in a gas enclosed in a glass tube containing two electrodes at a reduced pressure and to which a high voltage is applied ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["cations and anions","cations","electrons","cations and electrons"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>The type of reaction an alkanoic acid cannot undergo is&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["oxidation","combustion","decomposition","esterification"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>What is the pH of 2.5&nbsp;\u2715 10<sup>-3<\/sup> moldm<sup>3<\/sup> barium hydroxide solution ?&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["11.5","11.6","11.7","11.8"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>The complete oxidation of propan-1-ol yields<\/strong><\/p>","options":["CH<sub>3<\/sub>CH<sub>2<\/sub>CHO","CH<sub>3<\/sub>COCH<sub>3<\/sub>","CH<sub>3<\/sub>COOCH<sub>3<\/sub>","CH<sub>3<\/sub>CH<sub>2<\/sub>COOH"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>A physical change is exemplified by the&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["burning of bush","rusting of a metal","dissolution of calcium in water","heating of ammonium chloride"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>The number of neutrons in deuterium atom is\/are&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["0","1","2","3"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of these is the correct about methyl orange?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Yellow in excess aqueous hydrogen ions","pink in excess aqueous hydrogen ions","orange in excess aqueous hydrogen ions","colorless in excess aqueous hydrogen ions"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>which of these does not affect the rate of a particular chemical reaction?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The order of a particular chemical reaction","The size of particles of the reaction","The temperature of the reaction","The concentration of the reactants"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following will change the equilbrum constant of the reaction CO<sub>(g)<\/sub>+ H<sub>2<\/sub>O<sub>(l)<\/sub> &hArr; CO<sub>2(g)<\/sub>+ H<sub>2(g)<\/sub>?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Increase of temperature","Increase of concentration of CO","Removal of CO<sub>2<\/sub> from the mixture","Decrease of pressure"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>M<sub>(s)<\/sub>+ xH<sub>2<\/sub>SO<sub>4(aq)<\/sub>&nbsp;\u2192 M(SO<sub>4<\/sub>)<sub>x(aq)<\/sub> + xH<sub>2<\/sub> Which of the following elements will NOT undergo the above reaction?&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Zn","Na","Cu","Ca"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>How many isometric dichlorobenzenes are obtainable?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1","2","3","4"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>By accurate description , ozone in the reaction, O<sub>3(g)<\/sub> + H20<sub>(l)<\/sub>&nbsp;&rarr;&nbsp;H20<sub>(l)<\/sub> +2O<sub>2(g)<\/sub> is&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["dissipated to form oxygen","decomposed to form oxygen","oxidized to oxygen","reduced to oxygen"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>150cm<sup>3<\/sup> of nitrogen (II) oxide were sparked with 100cm<sup>3<\/sup> of oxygen, what volume of nitrogen (IV) oxide will be produced at s.t.p?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["100cm<sup>3<\/sup>","75cm<sup>3<\/sup>","50cm<sup>3<\/sup>","150cm<sup>3<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>In the electrolysis of acidified water using platinum electrodes, 1dm<sup>3<\/sup> of oxygen was collected at s.t.p by passing 4.5 amperes into the electrolytic cell. Calculate the time required to set his amount of gas free. [Molar volume of gas at s.t.p = 22.4dm<sup>3<\/sup>; 1 Faraday =9650 coulombs]<\/strong><\/p>","options":["40.4min","63.8min","55.5min","5.68min"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>Two plugs of glass wool soaked in concentrated ammonia and concentrated hydrochloric acid are placed at the opposite ends of a long tube such that the distance between them is 100cm<sup>3<\/sup>. The ratio of the distance covered by ammonia to that covered by hydrochloric acid when a white smoke is first noticed is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2.140","1.465","0.982","0.476"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>A motor truck releases an average of 5.0g CO into air for every km covered. How many molecules of CO will be emitted into the air if the truck travels 8km? [C=12; O=16; N<sub>A<\/sub>=6.02 x 10<sup>23<\/sup>]<\/strong><\/p>","options":["4.32 x 10<sup>22<\/sup>","2.48 x 10<sup>23<\/sup>","8.6 x 10<sup>23<\/sup>","6.82 x 10<sup>21<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A sample of an organic compound was weighed to be 0.250g and subjected to Kjeldahl treatment. The ammonia produced was neutralized by 27.0cm<sup>3<\/sup> of 0.100mol dm<sup>-3<\/sup>HCL. What is the percentage of nitrogen in the compound?[H=1; N=14]<\/strong><\/p>","options":["18.4%","17.8%","15.1%","13.3%"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Given the half -redox reaction O<sub>2<\/sub> + 4H<sup>+<\/sup> + 4e- \u2192 2H<sub>2<\/sub>O, how many moles of electron will be required to produce 3.0 x 10<sup>22<\/sup> molecules of water?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["0.05","0.10","0.15","2.0"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The quantum number L in an atom defines<\/strong><\/p>","options":["the shell K, L, M","orbitals","multiplicity","degeneracy of orbitals"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The hybridization of the central atom in a molecule<\/strong><\/p>","options":["dictates the shape of the molecules","shortens the sigma bond in the molecule","distorts the shape of the molecule","serves to explain the shape of the molecule"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Lithium with atomic number of 3 is a&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["strong reducing agent","strong oxidizing agent","weak reducing agent","weak oxidizing agent"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The correct name for HCOOC<sub>2<\/sub>H<sub>5<\/sub> is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["methylethanoate","ethylethanoate","ethylmethanoate","propylethanoate"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>When CaC<sub>2<\/sub> react with water, the organic product forms is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["ethanol","ethanoic acid","ethane","ethyne"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>100cm<sup>3<\/sup> of ethyne was mixed with 240cm<sup>3<\/sup> of oxygen in a combustion chamber. what volume of carbon(iv)oxide is produced?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["100cm<sup>3<\/sup>","24cm<sup>3<\/sup>","138cm<sup>3<\/sup>","192cm<sup>3<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The reduction potential of two electrodes are&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>X<sup>2+<\/sup> + 2e- ---&gt; X, E<sup>o<\/sup> = 0.042V<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Y<sup>+<\/sup> + e- ---&gt; Y, E<sup>o<\/sup> = 0.012V<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Calculate the free energy change of the cell that is made up of the electrodes [F = 96500 Coulomb mol<sup>-1<\/sup>]<\/strong><\/p>","options":["4.20kj","5.79kj","6.86kj","10.55kj"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of SF<sub>4<\/sub>, SiH<sub>4<\/sub>, CO<sub>2<\/sub>, ICl, CH<sub>2<\/sub>CI<sub>2<\/sub>, SO<sub>2<\/sub> and XeO<sub>3<\/sub> will not show the property of permanent dipole?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["CO<sub>2<\/sub> and SiH<sub>4<\/sub> only","SF<sub>4<\/sub> and SiH<sub>4<\/sub> only","CO<sub>2<\/sub>, SiH<sub>4<\/sub> and XeO<sub>3<\/sub> only","SF<sub>4<\/sub>, SiH<sub>4<\/sub>, CO<sub>2<\/sub> and ICl"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A sample of water weighs 200.00g&nbsp; at 298k. What is the volume of this quantity of water in cubic meters given that the density of water at 298k is 0.98gcm<sup>-3&nbsp;<\/sup>?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2.04 x 10<sup>-3<\/sup> m<sup>3<\/sup>","2.04 x 10<sup>-6<\/sup> m<sup>3<\/sup>","2.04 x 10<sup>-9<\/sup> m<sup>3<\/sup>","2.04 x 10<sup>-4<\/sup> m<sup>3<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The main product of electrophilic addition of HCL to 2-methylpropenen is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2-chloro-2-methylbutane","2-chloro-2-methylbutene","2-methyl-2-chloropropene","2-chloro-2-methylpropane"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following compound would you expect to show positive iodoform test?<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>(i) Butanone&nbsp;(ii) Propanoic&nbsp;(iii) Ethanol&nbsp;(iv) Benzaldehyde (v)But-2-one<\/strong><\/p>","options":["(i) and (ii)","(i) and (iii)","(iv) and (v)","(ii) and (ii)"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>An ion has a charge of +3. The nucleus of the ion has a mass of 120. The number of neutrons in the nucleus is 1.50 times that of the number of protons. How many electrons are in the ion?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["55","48","45","42"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Consider the following reactions<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>(i) LiOH + CO<sub>2<\/sub> ---&gt; Li<sub>2<\/sub>CO<sub>3<\/sub> + H<sub>2<\/sub>O<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>(ii) 2H<sub>2<\/sub> + O<sub>2<\/sub> ---&gt; 2H<sub>2<\/sub>O<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>(iii) 2Cu + O<sub>2<\/sub> ---&gt; 2CuO<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>(iv) HCI + AgNO3 ---&gt; AgCI + HNO<sub>3<\/sub><\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Which of this reactions are redox reactions?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["(i) and (iii) only","(i), (ii) and (iii) only","(i) and (iv) only","(ii) and (iii) only"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of this following metals cannot displace hydrogen from steam?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Copper","Iron","Strontium","Lithium"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Consider the exothermic reaction&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>2SO<sub>2(g)<\/sub> + O<sub>2(g)<\/sub> &lt;--&gt; 2SO<sub>2(g)<\/sub><\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>If the temperature of the reaction&nbsp; is reduced from 600<sup>o<\/sup>C to 300<sup>o<\/sup>C and no other changes take place then,<\/strong><\/p>","options":["the reaction rate increases","concentration of SO<sub>3<\/sub> decreases","concentration of SO<sub>3<\/sub> increases","SO<sub>2<\/sub> gas becomes unreactive"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>What condition favour the formation of the product for the endothermic reaction<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>&nbsp; &nbsp;N<sub>2<\/sub>O<sub>4(g)<\/sub>&nbsp;\u21c6 2NO<sub>2(g)<\/sub>&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["A decrease in pressure","A decrease in volume","An Increase in pressure","A constant Volume"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>What is the percentage yield of water if 0.90g of water is obtained when 29.0g of butane is burned in excess oxygen ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["0.02%","0.20%","2.0%","10.0%"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>The order of reactivity of five metals is P &gt; Q &gt; R &gt; S &gt; T. which of the following reactions can occur spontaneously ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["T + P<sup>+<\/sup> \u2192T<sup>+<\/sup> + P","Q + T<sup>+<\/sup> \u2192 Q<sup>+<\/sup> + T","R + Q<sup>+<\/sup> \u2192 R<sup>+<\/sup> + Q","T + R<sup>+<\/sup> \u2192 T<sup>+<\/sup> + R"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>An element Y has the electronic configuration of 1s<sup>2<\/sup> 2s<sup>2<\/sup> 2p<sup>6<\/sup> 3s<sup>2<\/sup> 3p<sup>3<\/sup>.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Y is a period III element","Y contains three electrons in the outer shell","Y is a transition metal","Y can engage in bonding with the s and p orbitals"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is NOT implicated as a major cause global warming ?&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["NO<sub>2<\/sub>","CO<sub>2<\/sub>","CFCl<sub>3<\/sub>","CF<sub>2<\/sub>Cl<sub>2<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the follwoing shows little or no net reaction when the volume of the system is decreased ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2O<sub>3(g)<\/sub> \u21c6 3O<sub>2(g)<\/sub>","2NO<sub>2(g)<\/sub> \u21c6 N<sub>2<\/sub>O<sub>4(g)<\/sub>","H<sub>2(g)<\/sub> + I<sub>2(g)<\/sub> \u21c6 2HI<sub>(g)<\/sub>","Pl<sub>3(g)<\/sub> + Cl<sub>2(g)<\/sub> \u21c6 PCl<sub>5(g)<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>A solution of 0.20 mole of NaBr and 0.20 mole of MgBr<sub>2<\/sub> in 2.0 dm<sup>3<\/sup> of water is to be analyzed.&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>How many moles of Pb(NO<sup>3<\/sup>)<sup>2<\/sup> must be added to precipitate all the bromide as insoluble PbBr<sup>2<\/sup> ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["0.30 mol","0.10 mol","0.20 mol","0.40 mol"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>&nbsp;A given volume of methane diffuses in 20s. How long will it take the same volume of sulphur (IV) oxide to diffuse under the same conditions ?<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>[C = 12, H = 1, S = 32, O = 16]<\/strong><\/p>","options":["5s","20s","40s","60s"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>The reaction, A&nbsp; + B&nbsp;&rarr;C , can be reprensented by the equation, r = K[A][B],<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>K in this equation is&nbsp; ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["proportionality constant","rate constant","equilibrium constant","Boltzmann constant"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>The reaction that takes place in Daniel cell is ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Zn \/ Zn<sup>2+<\/sup> \/\/ Cu<sup>2+<\/sup> \/ Cu","Zn \/ Zn<sup>2+<\/sup> \/\/ Cu \/ Cu<sup>2+<\/sup>","Zn<sup>2+<\/sup> \/ Zn \/\/ Cu<sup>2+<\/sup> \/ Cu","Zn<sup>2+<\/sup> \/ Zn \/\/ Cu \/ Cu<sup>2+<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the followings is composed of the elements, H, O, Al, and Si ?<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["Urea","Silica","Bauxite","Clay"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>which of the following is not a chemical reaction ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["burning of bush","rusting of iron","decay of bitter leaves","dissolution of potassium hydroxide pellets"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>A tertiary amine is ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["ethylamine","diethylamine","triethylamine","tetraethylamine"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following statements is true when sulphur atom forms its ion ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["it achieves an inert configuration","it transfers two electrons in the process","it accepts one electron in the process","it gets oxidized in the process"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>An aqueous solution of a crystalline salt reacts with dilute HCl to give a yellow precipitate and a gas that turned dichromate paper green.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The crystalline salt may be ?&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Na<sub>2<\/sub>S<sub>2<\/sub>O<sub>3<\/sub>.5H<sub>2<\/sub>O","Na<sub>2<\/sub>CO<sub>3<\/sub>.10H<sub>2<\/sub>O","Na<sub>2<\/sub>S","NaHCO<sub>3<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>The oxidation states of nitrogen in ammonium nitrate are ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["-3, +3","-3, +5","+3, -5","-3, 4"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of these reagents can confirm the presence of a triple bond ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["hypochlorous acid","bromine water","acidified KMnO<sub>4<\/sub>","Copper chloride"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>An excess 0.10 mol dm<sup>-3<\/sup>&nbsp; HCl was poured into a big beaker containing 2g of limestone. The unreacted acid required 25cm<sup>3<\/sup> of 0.10 mol dm<sup>-3<\/sup>&nbsp; potassium carbonate to neutralize it. What was the original volume of the acid?<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>[ Ca = 4-, C = 12, O = 16]<\/strong><\/p>","options":["250cm<sup>3<\/sup>","260cm<sup>3<\/sup>","400cm<sup>3<\/sup>","450cm<sup>3<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong><sup>226<\/sup><sub>88<\/sub> Ra&nbsp;&nbsp;&rarr;<sup>X<\/sup><sub>86<\/sub> Rn +&nbsp;&alpha;-particles<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>What is the value of x in the nuclear reaction ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["226","220","222","174"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>In the electrolysis of copper (II) sulphate using copper electrodes, the processes that occur at the anode and cathode respectively are :<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["dissolution and evolution","dissolution and deposition","deposition and evolution","evolution and deposition"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"}]